PATRICK KIMARO

A passionate software development, innovation, user experience design, and motivated self-starter with experience in youth exploring the STEM Innovations space with a proven ability to work with difficult tech work and provide a high service level to clients.

42041, Dar es Salaam Dar es Salaam, Tanzania (255) 658 962 000 pkimaro15@gmail.com lam_kimaro_bts

EXPERIENCE

CREATECH — Co-founder

Jan 2019 - PRESENT

A non-government organization working to raise the profile of STEM Education in Tanzanian Schools.

iPF Software. Dar es salaam — FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Nov 2021- Nov 2022

Font End Dev at **iPF** software who is passionate about creating attention-to-detail user experiences. I believe that great-looking and familiar user interfaces are crucial to providing value and creating loyal users.

MiTz Innovation. Dar es salaam — Instructor

May 2020 - Oct 2020

Training and teaching eight public secondary schools and one private, practical science activities and organizing the WIN Event science concert in Tanga Region

ROBOTECH LABs, Dar es salaam — IT TECHNICIAN

Feb 2020 - Sept 2020

I worked at Robotech labs as an IT Technician and STEM EDUCATOR. I firmly believe that I make a significant impact on the company because I have grown skilled and experienced in STEM Activities.

EDUCATION

Dar es salaam Institute o Technology, Dar Es Salaam — *Ordinary Diploma in Information Technology*

Nov 2020 - present

Relevant Coursework: Basic Electronics Designing, Fundamental Arduino Programming, Electrical circuit and Installation, Computer Networking, Technical drawing, Algebra, and Technical Communication skills, C & C++ programming, VB.Net, Operating system, Computer maintenance, Computer architecture.

Tanga Technical school, Tanga —Ordinary Level Education

lan 2016 - Nov 2019

Relevant Coursework: Basic Mathematics, Chemistry, Geography, Engineering science,

SKILLS

- Project Coordination:
- Innovation Skills
- Strategic Planning
- Event Planning
- free-hand design

AWARDS

Secondary Category Innovator Winner, MAKISATU.

National Government Competition for Science, technology, and Innovation of young students.

Innovator Grant Winner, COSTECH

Winner of the Tanzania Commission for Science and Technology, a parastatal organization affiliated with Tanzania grant for project progress.

LANGUAGES

English: Advanced

Swahili: Fluent

France: Beginner

REFEREES

Grayson julius - founding partner

iPF softwares

graysonjulius@ipfsotwares.com

+2557 1228 8231

Kelvin Paul - Co-founder

MiTZ innovations

kelvinpaul@mitzinnovations.com

+2556 5306 8346

Shaukatali Z. Hussein - founder

Robotech Labs Tz

shaukat@robotech.co.tz

+2557 8896 1951

Hassan Mshinda, PhD- independent Consultant

Fondation Botnar

edwardlwidiko@projektinspire.com

+2557 1286 5206